<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE knimeNode PUBLIC "-//UNIKN//DTD KNIME Node 2.0//EN" "http://www.knime.org/Node.dtd">
<knimeNode icon="./sumformula.png" type="Other">
	<name>Sum Formula</name>

	<shortDescription>
		Node to generate molecular formulas based on
		a given mass input.
    </shortDescription>

	<fullDescription>
		<intro>Generates sum formulas based on a given mass. The formula generator assumes 
			input masses to be major isotopic masses.
			<br/>
			<br/>
			Generated sum formulas can be filtered by the nitrogen rule, element ratio rule, and
			by element number restriction. For details on the implemented options, please see the
			"seven golden rules" by Kind et al., 2007. The following excerpts are taken from the publication.
			<br/>
			<br/>
			"The nitrogen rule states that an odd nominal molecular mass implies also an odd number of nitrogens. 
			This rule should only be used with nominal (integer) masses. When using accurate mass measurements 
			this rule becomes unreliable in mass ranges higher than 500 Da."
			<br/>
			<br/>
			"The maximum element count can be restricted in a heuristic manner by using the provided sets of element
			minima und maxima that were derived from NIST and Wiley mass spectra and DNP entries. Maximum element counts 
			are defined for the mass ranges at smaller 500 Da, 1000 Da, 2000 Da, 3000 Da by taking the higher value found 
			in either of the two databases."
			<br/>
			<br/>
			"More than 99.7% of all formulas were included with H/C ratios between 0.2–3.1. This range is called the 'common range'. 
			However, a number of chemical classes fall out of this range. The 'extended ranges' covers 99.99% of all formulas in 
			the used database (H vs C 0.1–6). There are extreme cases for which rules of typical H vs C ratios may be overridden, e.g. 
			for the study of fullerenes, which have an extremely low hydrogen/carbon ratio such as in C78H12Cl2N2."
			<br/>
			<br/>
			Sum formulas that do not contain a single Carbon atom are always included.
			<br/>
			<br/>
			DISABLED Options: 'All elements' and 'Exclude elements' are currently not supported because the
			matrix required for the calculation exceeds the memory limit of the virtual machine: Math.pow(2, size).</intro>
		<option name="Column with masses">Mass column in input table.</option>
		<option name="All elements (DISABLED)">Whether to use all elements for the calculation.</option>
		<option name="Include elements">Whether to use a custom set of elements.</option>
		<option name="Exclude elements (DISABLED)">Whether to use all elements excluding a set of elements.</option>
		<option name="Elements">The comma-separated set of elements to be included or excluded.</option>
		<option name="Carbon limits">The allowed minimum and maximum number of carbon element counts.</option>
		<option name="Hydrogen limits">The allowed minimum and maximum number of hydrogen element counts.</option>
		<option name="Other limits">The allowed minimum and maximum number of other element counts.</option>
		<option name="Mass tolerance">The mass tolerance in 'amu'.</option>
		<option name="Nitrogen rule">Apply the nitrogen rule.</option>
		<option name="Element ratio rule">Apply the element ratio check rule.</option>
		<option name="Element restriction">Apply element occurrence restrictions.</option>
	</fullDescription>

	<ports>
		<inPort index="0" name="Mass input">Table with molecular masses.</inPort>
		<outPort index="0" name="Input with sum forumlas">Input table plus calculated sum
			formulas.</outPort>
	</ports>
</knimeNode>
