<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE knimeNode PUBLIC "-//UNIKN//DTD KNIME Node 2.0//EN" "http://www.knime.org/Node.dtd">
<knimeNode icon="./sssearch.png" type="Manipulator">
    <name>Substructure Search</name>
    <shortDescription>Filters molecules based on a fragment</shortDescription>
    <fullDescription>
        <intro>
            This node allows to draw a fragment in the dialog. Upon execution
            the molecules from the input table are divided into two sets, one with
            all molecules that contain the fragments, the other with all molecules
            that do not contain it.<br/><br/>
            The substructure search matches stereochemistry if defined. The total number of matched substructures is limited to five.<br/><br/>
            The fragments are passed between JChemPaint and the CDK in SMILES format. Hence, 
            if the fragment string is provided as flow variable, the input must be in SMILES format as well.         
        </intro>
        <option name="Sketcher">Use the control options to assemble a structure. If a previously
        drawn molecule does not show up when opening the dialog, you may need to scroll down the editor pane.</option>
        <option name="Column with molecules">Select the column that contains the molecules.</option>
        <option name="Match charges">Matches charges.</option>
        <option name="Exact match">Exact stereochemistry match: Undefined chiral centers in the query molecule must also be undefined in the target molecule.</option>
        <option name="Highlight substructure">Highlights all found substructures in the molecules.</option>
    </fullDescription>
    <ports>
        <inPort index="0" name="Molecules">Table that contains at least one column with CDK molecules.</inPort>
        <outPort index="0" name="Molecules with fragment">Table with all molecules that contain the fragment.</outPort>
        <outPort index="1" name="Molecules without fragment">Table with all molecules that do not contain the fragment.</outPort>
    </ports>
</knimeNode>
